Om Sharan

Manager - Cloud Solutions at i2k2 Networks (P) Ltd

Summary

An optimistic marketer who can market and sell anything under the sun given it has a price. Well jokes apart, I did my B.E in Electronics & Communication from VTU, Bangalore and a PGPM (Marketing) from Alliance University, Bangalore. I have 5 years of experience in sales. Currently, holding the position of Manager Cloud Solutions, selling high end Cloud Solutions of i2k2 Networks Pvt Ltd, I can boast of a 360 degree understanding of the various aspects of business namely, Marketing, HR and Finance. I have had a decorated career with plenty of awards and recognition both in academics and corporates. Specialties: Market Research, Business Development ,Sales, Marketing Communications, Branding, Customer relations

Experience

Consultant Cloud Solutions at i2k2 Networks (P) Ltd

March 2013 - Present (2 years 4 months)

Sales for Enterprise Cloud Solutions (VMware,Zimbra Collaboration Suit, Cloud Servers powered with VMware ESXI, vSphere).

Center Services(Co-location, DR Solutions, Backup Solution). • Requirement Analysis, Solution Design and Suggestion. • Marketing Research & Competition Analysis.

2 recommendations available upon request

Manager - Cloud Solutions at i2k2 Networks (P) Ltd

March 2013 - Present (2 years 4 months)

• Lead,Influence,motivate and enable a team of two member to contribute in sales. • Sales for Enterprise Cloud Solutions (VMware,Zimbra Collaboration Suit, Cloud Servers powered

with VMware ESXI, vSphere). • Data Center Services(Co-

location, DR Solutions, Backup Solution). • Requirement Analysis, Solution Design and Suggestion. • Marketing Research & Competition Analysis.

Branch Sales Manager at Navigator systems

December 2011 - March 2013 (1 year 4 months)

Dealing with SUN,IBM,DELL,HP (Servers, Storage, Tape Solution, Backup solution & cloud services), EMC(Unified Storage), Cisco(Switches & Routers), HP(Switches), Responsibilities:- - Developing sales plans & value added solutions designed to assure achievement of agreed to volume, market share and profit objectives. - Identify the buying power and analyzing the share of wallet for servers and work towards increasing the same. - Working towards Enterprise Solution approach to the customer. - Mapping client's requirements & providing them customized business solutions through technical and commercial proposals - Selling wide array of SUN,IBM,HP,Dell's offerings in Storage, Servers, Networking, End to End

Computing, IT Automaton like Managed Services , Infrastructure Consulting Services , Asset Management , Data centre solutions etc. - Identifying opportunities in the accounts, qualifying, advancing leads and closing. - Preparing Commercial Proposals, sales / business collateral, negating the deal with customer (technical & commercial). - Responsible for managing the relationships in the account and win over decision makers / influencers. - Close the deals (technical & commercial), with detailed order terms and set customer expectations. - Set up branch at Delhi and lead a team of sales personal to contribute effectively in the top line.

1 recommendation available upon request

Management Trainee at Century Plyboards (I) Ltd

May 2011 - November 2011 (7 months)

JOB HIGHLIGHTS Sales, collection for Plywood. Supervise a team of Sales Executive, Project Executive and Sales Assistant. Coaching, and training the team. Develop sales strategy for market expansion and market penetration. Identification of prospects. Make presentations to clients and close sales.. Build good relationships with potential and existing clients. Work with team to achieve sales performance targets. Managing key accounts and Influencers. Organizing Influencer meet and making attractive schemes to boost the sales. To manage channel network/sales of the branch/location in the assigned territory. Manage Channel Partners. Co-ordinate for Processing of Orders. Support POP Material Distribution. Coordinate with other teams for Leads Management. Co-ordinate for Complaint Handling. Provide Information for databases and MIS. Compliance and adherence of statutory norms

1 recommendation available upon request

Intern at Metis ERC (I) Pvt Ltd

April 2010 - June 2010 (3 months)

Technical Associate at Wipro Pvt ltd

August 2008 - July 2009 (1 year)

JOB HIGHLIGHTS Develop various programs Provide technical support and solution

Volunteer Experience

Hiring at Sapient

May 2010 - June 2010 (2 months)

Helped them in the hiring process

Languages

Hindi

Skills & Expertise

Business Development

Market Research
Program Management
Management
Channel Partners
Competitive Analysis
Cloud Computing
Business Intelligence
Business Strategy
Selling
Go-to-market Strategy

Channel

Marketing Management

Financial Modeling

Marketing Strategy

Enterprise Software

Key Account Management

Data Center

Sales

Marketing

Networking

Sales Operations

Team Management

Courses

Independent Coursework

MBA Marketing

BE E & C

Education

Alliance Business School, Bangalore 2009-2011

Post-graduate Diploma, Management (PGDM)(Marketing), 2009 - 2011

Visvesvaraya Technological University

BE, electronics and communication, 2004 - 2008

Interests

marketing management, innovation, engineering, musical instrument, cricket

Om Sharan

Manager - Cloud Solutions at i2k2 Networks (P) Ltd

Linked in.

4 people have recommended Om

"Trying to sum up OM in a brief recommendation is a near impossible. In Hindu mythology the word OM is very pure, similarly the OM here is very pure from his heart He is really very good at Business Development and client's handling. His dedication for his work is ultimate, One of the most important attribute I forgot to mentioned about his knowledge and business skills. He is best at optimization of resources even he had helped me in clearly my vision. I wish him Good Luck for his future endeavor."

— **Dilpreet Singh**, *Consultant Cloud Solution*, *i2k2 Networks (P) Ltd*, worked directly with Om at i2k2 Networks (P) Ltd

"Om is as creative & hard-working a guy as you can find. He always has a smile on his face & looking to improve his craft constantly by reading & reaching out to those around him. He always help you with providing his feedback. He is on the forefront of identifying new opportunities to connect with businesses & prospective. He certainly has a passion for everything that he does... Keep doing dude!"

— **Prashant Priyam**, *Manager - Enterprise Cloud Solutions*, *i2k2 Networks* (*P*) *Ltd*, worked with Om at i2k2 Networks (P) Ltd

"Om Sir is a person who leads by example. His immense knowledge, managerial process, his foresight, and his fantastic planning and organizational capability make working with him a pleasure. I've learnt so much from him for which I am very grateful. He has definitely been by far one of my best managers. A through professional along with being a fantastic human being! Last but not the least He is the Man behind my professional Success!!"

— Ramshakal Kumar Yadav, Senior Marketing / Technical Executive, Navigator Systems Pvt, managed Om at Navigator systems

"Om is a smart working person,I know very well but some person wants through back to Om.Not a single person know that fate is own."

— **Syed S.**, *Marketing Manager, Bihar, Patna, Royale Touch Luxury Laminates*, worked directly with Om at Century Plyboards (I) Ltd

Contact Om on LinkedIn